♪♪
Okay, ladies and gentlemen,
all around us are
the soundstages
where your favorite movie and
television shows are created.
And right up ahead
there on Stage 15,
Catherine Welden
is currently filming.
Here, Catherine, let me.
Come on.
Ron, you know me.
It's always better
if I do it myself.
How's that boy of yours, huh?
Getting bigger?
Oh, yeah, just
started high school.
That's great.
As sweet as ever, Catherine.
How did you get onto the lot
and into my dressing room?
No "Hi, Peter, you look
great, I missed you"?
I'm about five minutes away
from shooting a commercial, Peter.
For Catherine Welden Cosmetics?
What do you want?
I saw your fourth-quarter sales
in the Journal... $12 million.
I'm... I'm thrilled
for you, Katie.
Ron, would you tell
them I'll just be a minute?
Of course.
Thank you.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
All right, why are you here?
I knew you'd want to see me.
I mean, after all,
we were partners.
Is that what you're
calling it these days?
Of course.
We were living together when
we both came up with the idea
of creating a cosmetic
line in your name.
You had nothing to do with that.
I think your memory's
a little vague.
You weren't exactly
sober in those days.
So?
Are you threatening me?
Catherine... your
secret is safe with me.
I'd never want anyone to know
that you're a woman who drank
herself out of a movie career,
disappeared from sight,
and then emerged sober
and beautiful with a
successful cosmetic line.
If you think you're
getting a penny from me...
I want half.
For what?
Get out.
Oh, my, my, my.
Trust me, Katie, you don't
want me to take you to court.
Katie, I've got great...
Peter.
Hi, Jackie.
How nice... your little
sister's still around
to pick up after you.
Get out of here!
Think it over, Katie.
I'll be in touch.
What's he doing here?
Ben?
Hi.
Thousands and thousands
and thousands of dollars
I'm gonna owe the
government this year,
just thousands and
thousands and thousands.
Why don't you let your
accountant sort that out?
These new tax laws, you
can't hardly write off anything...
I mean anything.
Why aren't you worried?
I'm in a slightly
lower tax bracket.
You'd think I could
deduct something.
All I do is work.
Is this your way of telling me
you're not coming
to Los Angeles?
You going to Los Angeles?
Ben, I told you I was going.
Oh.
Aren't you coming?
Oh, just thousands and
thousands and thousands of dollars.
I wouldn't be any fun.
Oh, my friend Jackie
is dying to meet you.
Remember, I told you her
sister is Catherine Welden?
Oh, I know.
I bet I've seen The River
Runs Deep six times.
Well?
I'm a huge Catherine Welden fan.
Oh, I just can't.
It's just thousands
and thousands
and thousands and
thousands of dollars.
- It's just...
- Okay, when I see her,
I'm gonna tell her
you're a huge fan.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, this dinner for two
at Renoir's... isn't
that wh... isn't that
where I took you
after the Morgan trial?
You can't deduct that.
Why not?
You took me there
for my birthday,
and we didn't talk business.
Well, I was thinking about it.
While you were holding my hand?
Well, they don't
have to know that.
♪♪
Truce?
How nice.
Katie, I'm delighted.
Come in.
Looks familiar.
It is familiar.
Peter, please.
Drink?
I came over to...
After what happened
today... I was abrupt.
I apologize.
It's my fault; I
should have called.
I haven't forgotten how
close we once were,
so if you need money, I
would be more than happy
to help you.
How generous of you, huh?
You can't expect more, Peter.
You want to know what I expect?
I expect $4 million.
Or what, you'll sue?
You had nothing to
do with my company.
I'll walk into court
with pictures that will
make the front page
of the National Informer.
Remember how you looked
when we were living together?
Drop dead!
Not exactly the youthful,
glamorous image
your public has in mind
when they buy Catherine
Welden Cosmetics
expecting to look
exactly like you.
Good-bye, image.
Good-bye, profits.
Thank you.
Jackie!
Oh, you are positively skinny.
Oh, you don't look a day older.
You liar.
- Oh!
- Come on in.
Oh, are you okay?
Remember how
embarrassed you were?
Yes.
Oh...
Tell me about Ben.
Is he cute?
Very cute.
Does he lavish you
with expensive gifts?
He's very cute.
Oh, he's a big
fan of your sister's.
Who isn't?
So, what about you?
What lucky guy is
sweeping you off your feet?
Well, my last date
was, uh, let me see...
about seven months
ago, this Saturday.
I think this is what
they call a "slump."
Oh, no!
Well, you need some fun.
Let's spend tomorrow together.
Ooh, I'd love that.
Oh... but first,
I have to listen to a
new ad agency pitch
and then interview
someone for a job.
Oh, you're just so corporate.
I know.
Isn't it great?
$12 million in national sales.
Some might say
a staggering figure
for a company only
two years young.
- The way it sounds.
- True.
I believe, however, that you
have just touched the surface.
Good.
- This sounds even better.
- I submit to you
that this company
does not sell cosmetics.
No, it sells your
image, Ms. Welden.
Hmm.
And that's what we propose
to do with our campaign.
We are going to make
your products as sexy
as the woman herself.
- I like that talk.
- I'll vouch for that.
Don't run to the bank just yet.
What the hell are
you doing here?
Edgar, your divorce
is working out so much
- better than your marriage.
- Someone call security, now!
- Calm down. Calm down.
- Get him out of here!
I'm just making
a quick delivery.
I'm legally entitled to 30% of
Catherine Welden Cosmetics.
What?!
If I don't have $4
million by tomorrow,
I'm suing this company,
and this will be Exhibit "A."
- You snake.
- What are you talking about?
Be interesting to see
what would happen
to Catherine's image
and your investment
if I dragged these
pictures into court.
Oh, my God.
Never saw your ex-wife
like that before,
did you, Edgar?
Edgar, please!
It was a long time ago.
Katie, all those fans who
idolize you... how do you
think they'd feel
seeing you drunk and
rolling around in bed with me?
Think about it.
Peter! Your door's open!
Peter, you left your door op...
Oh, Julie! The police
think she killed Peter.
And our attorney's out of town.
Would you act as
counsel for Katie
while the police question her?
Please?
- Of course.
- Oh, thank you.
So you recognize this
makeup bag, Miss Welden,
or any of its contents?
Yes.
So, it is your bag then, ma'am?
- Yes, but I...
- Detective Stoner,
this makeup kit is
hardly sufficient grounds
for an indictment, no
matter whom it belongs to.
Mr. Bates was in
the process of filing
a multimillion-dollar
lawsuit against your client.
And there was an eyewitness.
What?
That's impossible.
A neighbor of the
victim's saw your car
leaving the murder
scene at exactly 6:30 p.m.
- I wasn't anywhere...
- May, may I
speak to Miss Welden for
a moment alone, please?
Be my guest.
My God... What's
happening to me?
You're going to be
all right, Catherine.
We'll straighten this out.
I left that makeup kit
at Peter's last night.
Julie, I didn't kill him.
I wasn't there tonight.
Obviously, the
neighbor was mistaken,
but I'm afraid that's enough
to file murder charges.
Julie... What do I do?
- Will you represent me?
- I'm...
a prosecuting
attorney, Catherine.
You need a defense lawyer.
Well, then get me the best.
And I mean the very best.
H-Hello?
Oh, no, I woke you.
I'm sorry.
- Yeah, I was just...
- Sleeping?
I know. I'm sorry.
How are the taxes going?
Oh, just thousands and
thousands and thousands of dollars.
I, um, I saw Catherine Welden.
What?
I saw Catherine Welden.
Oh, good. Did you
tell her I'm a big fan?
Yes, I did, and she wants to
fly you out here to meet her.
She wants to pay my
airplane fare to Los Angeles?
Yes, she's very
anxious to talk with you,
and I'd love to see you, too.
Maybe I will. I'd get to
meet her and see you...
Maybe I can do
a little business.
Make it a business trip.
You know, deductible?
I think I can arrange that.
What did your
sister see in this jerk?
Oh, what can I tell you, Ben?
Peter was a
good-looking hustler.
He took advantage
of Catherine at a very
low point in her life.
She had gained a lot of
weight. She was drinking heavily.
Y-You wouldn't have
even recognized her.
Her career seemed to be over.
Hmm.
Uh, why were these pictures
he took of her so important?
Ben, Catherine became
a star playing the loyal wife...
The good, beautiful woman.
That's her image.
These pictures are so awful.
Well, they could destroy
her and our company.
Well...
who else was at this
meeting when, uh,
when this Peter came in?
Well, aside from Katie and me,
there was her personal
manager, Gil Altman,
and also Edgar.
Catherine's ex-husband.
Well, what was her
ex-husband doing there?
Well, Edgar and Katie have
remained very good friends.
Edgar's a brilliant businessman,
and he's the company's
financial advisor.
Oh, pretty soon, I'd better
go meet my new client.
Ben, I can't thank you enough
for coming out here so fast.
Now, I know why Julie's
been bragging about you.
Yeah.
So, you were bragging on me?
I told her you were cute.
So, what do you think?
I think I'm okay.
I'm talking about the case.
Oh.
Well, if I were Catherine
Welden's manager,
and my income were
tied to her company,
those pictures would
make me very nervous.
I'll go talk to Mr. Altman.
- I'll fly Conrad out.
- Why?
You know I'm going to
want to stay close to this.
- Oh, I...
- Jackie and I are like sisters.
Well, okay, but promise
me you'll be careful.
♪♪
Mr. Matlock!
Ms. Welden.
Uh, I didn't know you were
in your, uh, uh... swimming.
I-I can, uh... I can come back.
First of all, my
friends call me Katie.
- Oh.
- And secondly, I swim laps twice a day,
so you're gonna have to get
used to meeting by the pool.
Oh, I, I could get used to that.
Something wrong?
You have a birthmark.
I've never noticed that
in any of your movies.
Makeup.
Oh!
Would you like some iced tea?
Uh, yeah. Yeah. Ooh...
- So...
- Well... Shall we get started?
Yeah. Yeah, this, uh, um...
Uh, th-this, uh, Peter
Bates, how did you meet him?
My sister introduced
us, um, at a Lakers game.
She had season tickets.
His seats were
right behind hers.
I've seen pictures of him.
He was a nice-looking fellow.
He was a hustler
looking for a meal ticket.
Until I got sober, I didn't
see him for what he was.
Well, you, you quit drinking.
That's, that's the main...
main thing. Oh, yeah.
Did he help you, uh,
create your cosmetics?
Absolutely not.
Uh, why, why did you go visit
him the night before the murder?
I thought if I offered him
some money, he might go away.
Yeah.
Th-That's when you
left your makeup kit?
Now, I know the
police have a witness
who says she saw my
car the night of the murder.
What I don't know is whether
she's lying or just mistaken.
Yeah, yeah.
- Now, Ben.
- Uh-huh?
May I call you Ben?
Why, yes.
Ben, uh, you know how
much I appreciate you
coming out here to defend me.
Oh, I, I wouldn't miss this.
Would you mind?
I'd like to... see
every document
and hear about every phone
call that pertains to this case.
Would that be all right?
Why, yes, that
would be all right.
That would be fine.
You'd be involved.
Of course, I don't
want to be a pest.
Oh, you couldn't be a pest.
I mean, a mosquito's a pest,
and you're not a mosquito.
Hmm. You have nice hair.
Oh, well... You
have nice hair, too.
I'll, I'll, uh...
Bye, Ben.
Let me know if there's
anything I can do to help.
Okay.
Aren't you going
to start the car?
Oh!
Thank you.
Ms. March, please come in.
Hello, Mr. Altman.
I really appreciate your
seeing me on such short notice.
Not at all. I just
want to help Katie.
Please, sit down.
My goodness... you certainly
know a lot of celebrities.
Well, I've been in
the biz for 20 years.
And, uh, I understand
that right now
Catherine is your only client.
Well, Katie's career is,
uh, certainly a handful.
Aren't those the, um,
photographs of Catherine
that, uh, Peter gave you?
Yes, they are.
I saw them.
Catherine Welden.
Every man's dream.
Shocked the hell out of me.
Well, no one else
is going to see these.
I hope not.
If those photographs
were made public,
it would ruin both of you.
- Both of us?
- Oh, yes.
Catherine's image is
what gets her acting roles
and sells her makeup
and pays your mortgage...
You know, Ms. March,
people think agents and
managers in this town are bad.
But, uh, not that bad.
Now, don't you think it
would have been stupid of me
to kill Peter and
frame my client?
I mean, isn't that kind of like,
uh, shooting myself in the foot?
I don't think
Catherine was framed.
Who are these people?
The couples I had at
my house for a barbecue
the night Peter was killed.
Just in case you want
to verify my whereabouts.
That looks delicious.
- Well, it is.
- Yeah?
Well, I've got to tell you,
I have never heard a wife
speak so highly of
her ex-husband, ever.
Well, I adore Katie, too.
And I've got to hand it to you,
most men wouldn't look after
their wives' business affairs,
uh, after the divorce.
Well... our, uh, our
marriage is over,
but our friendship isn't.
Besides, I own a
piece of the company.
- Uh...
- May I bring you something?
Yes, some soup... anything.
I bet you hated it when, uh,
Catherine left with
that, uh, Peter Bates.
Broke my heart to
see her with that creep.
How long did she live with him?
What... year, year and a half.
Didn't you try to stop her?
Well... she wouldn't listen.
See, her career was
in trouble. She'd, uh...
Well, she started drinking.
And he made her feel young.
See, beautiful
women, like Catherine...
they know that beauty won't
last, and it terrifies them.
In a way, that... that
face is her curse.
I know a lot of women who'd
like to be cursed like that.
Oh... thank you.
I bet you could have
cheerfully wrung his neck
when he walked in there with
those pictures of Catherine.
You're all right,
Mr. Matlock, you know that?
- You know what I mean.
- Yeah.
What is that you're having?
- Steak and mushrooms.
- Hmm.
You want a bite?
Um, well...
Mmm...
You'd like to know where I
was that night, wouldn't you?
I wouldn't mind.
Well, I was in there,
losing my shirt...
playing bridge, all night long.
Hmm...
Oh...
Mmm... mmm.
Thank you.
What's wrong?
What is it?
Well... I found a letter
over at Peter Bates' house.
What kind of a letter?
A love letter.
Poor Catherine...
What Peter put her through.
It wasn't from her.
It was from Jackie.
Jackie... Flemming wrote
a love letter to Peter?
She was the one who
introduced Catherine to him.
Jackie Flemming
was in love with Peter,
and she never told me?!
Oh, don't do that.
Jackie... didn't kill Peter.
You can't be sure.
Yes, I am.
She didn't.
Well, I'm going to have
to talk with her, anyway.
No, uh, I'll talk to her.
She... she tells me everything.
Except about Peter.
No doubt about
it, Ben is adorable.
Ah, it must be his white hair.
So distinguished.
And he's so real.
Most L.A. lawyers
are so plastic.
You've got to get
him to move to L.A.
He'll make a fortune.
Then you'll get married
and you and I can see
each other every day...
Why didn't you tell me about
your relationship with Peter?
Ben found a letter you wrote
to Peter three years ago.
You were in love
with him, Jackie.
I, uh... I never
lied to you, Julie.
You know that Peter had
season basketball tickets
in the row behind mine.
Catherine mentioned that to Ben.
And we struck up an acquaintance
and then a friendship...
And then we began dating.
Was he interested in you?
Only as a friend.
We never even kissed.
Then why did you
write that letter?
Because as good
as I am in business,
that's how bad I am about men.
A man pays a
little attention to me
and I fall head over
heels in two minutes.
Does Catherine
know you dated Peter?
- No!
- Oh, Jackie, why...
why didn't you just tell her
that you had feelings for him?
Because he didn't share them.
That romance happened so fast.
Ten days after I
introduced them,
Peter moved in with Catherine.
And she was crazy about him.
And so were you?
Oh, yeah.
I just couldn't tell her.
Not even after she left Peter?
I didn't want her to know
how messed-up I had gotten
over a guy who
turned out to be a bum.
You want to know the worst part?
Now that I think about it,
I'm convinced that Peter
struck up a friendship with me
so he could meet Katie.
Jackie, do you know
how this could look
to people who don't know you?
Julie, do you know
where I was that night?
In my office, in a meeting.
That's the truth.
You must believe me.
Ben, thanks for
coming over so fast.
Oh, yeah.
Come over here.
I want to show you
something I found
- in this police report.
- Okay.
I found something. I don't
know whether it means anything.
What?
Boy, you, you're really
hands-on on this, aren't you?
Well, Ben, when I left Peter,
it came down to
me making a choice.
I could be one of those
actresses you read about
that wallow in self-pity when
their career slows down, or...
I could take
responsibility for my life.
You're a fighter.
Oh, yeah.
So, what'd you find?
Right here... the makeup
kit I left at Peter's...
- The police list six items.
- Yeah?
Well, a concealer's missing.
There should be
seven items in this kit.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
Well, why would someone
steal your makeup?
Ms. March. Hi.
Hi, Faith.
I'm sorry. Miss
Flemming isn't in.
Actually, I wanted
to talk to you.
Sure, what about?
Well, you know that
I'm helping Mr. Matlock
investigate Peter Bates' murder.
Oh. I didn't really know him.
I know that.
But on the night he was killed,
Miss Flemming
interviewed a man named...
Ken Evans.
Did Mr. Evans kill...?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
I just need to know
where everybody was.
Now, the meeting was at 6:00?
Well, it was
supposed to be at 6:00.
It wasn't?
Well, Mr. Evans called
and said he had car trouble,
and Miss Flemming
asked me to go pick him up.
How long were you gone?
Almost an hour.
Detective Stoner...
did you find any evidence of
Catherine Welden's presence
at Peter Bates' house
on the night of the murder?
Yes, sir, I did.
I'd like to show you
People's Exhibit 27...
This makeup kit...
And ask if you can identify it.
This has my mark.
I found this makeup kit
in Mr. Bates' living room.
Did you discover who owns it?
Yes, sir, we did.
See, that kit looks exactly like
every other makeup kit
sold throughout the city
by the Catherine Welden
Cosmetic Company.
- Uh-huh?
- But there's one difference.
The regular kits
that are sold at retail
have plastic tops
that are painted gold.
This kit has solid gold tops.
There was only one
specifically made that way.
And who was this made for?
Catherine Welden.
She's the only one that has a
makeup kit with solid gold tops.
Thank you.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Your witness, Mr. Matlock.
Thank you.
Uh, Detective Stoner...
uh... there's no real way
of telling when this
makeup kit was left
at, uh, Mr. Bates's
house, is there?
No, not really.
It could have been
left there a month ago
or a week ago
or the night before
Mr. Bates was murdered.
Couldn't it?
Yes.
And my client
told you that she
left this makeup kit
at Mr. Bates's house the
night before the murder.
She had brought Mr. Bates
a gift, a kind of peace offering.
- Right?
- Yeah.
She said something
about a crystal elephant.
Which makes no sense, since
no such elephant was found
on the premises.
Your Honor, would
you instruct the witness
to just answer my questions
without editorializing?
Detective Stoner, you've
appeared in my courtroom before.
You know better than that.
Excuse me, Your Honor.
Ask for a recess.
What?
Why?
Just trust me.
- Please.
- Mr. Matlock?
Uh... right there, Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock?
Um... Uh, Your Honor?
Uh, defense would like
to re... request a recess
until tomorrow morning.
In the middle of counsel's
cross-examination?
May I ask why?
Uh, yes, sir.
Your Honor, I-I ate
one of those fat
California hot dogs
with some real
strong onions on it,
and they're kind of
coming back on me.
Maybe you noticed?
This, uh, court is adjourned
till 9:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Why did I do that?
Because I asked you to.
That's so sweet of you.
Are you going to tell me
why you asked me to do that?
I can't tell you right now.
I'll tell you later.
But meet me at
your hotel at 6:00.
Promise.
I really don't want to have
this conversation with you.
Well, then, why are we here?
Even now, you won't
admit it, will you?
What?
You were at Peter's on
the night of the murder.
The crystal elephant, Jackie...
The one that
Catherine gave Peter,
the one the police
couldn't find...
It's in your den.
You lied. You lied to
me. You lied to Ben.
You lied to your sister.
You can't believe I killed him.
What's going on?
Well, I went to Peter's
house to offer him $100,000
for those pictures of Catherine.
Since-Since all he
wanted was money,
I thought he'd grab it.
And he would have.
But he was dead
when I got there.
You must believe me!
When I saw him, I
panicked and I ran!
What about the elephant?
Well, it was there
sitting in a box
with a note from Catherine.
I-I took it so-so I
could protect her.
Why didn't you tell
Catherine you were there?
Because I don't know
whether she killed Peter or not.
I'm sorry I'm late.
The freeway is a parking lot.
Will you tell me
what's going on?
It was Jackie who was
at Peter Bates' house
on the night of the
murder, not Catherine.
How do you know?
Jackie...
Jackie took the
crystal elephant.
She took it home with
her, but she didn't kill Peter.
Was she driving Catherine's car?
Yes. Jackie had loaned
her car to her secretary.
Catherine's car just
happened to be there,
so Jackie borrowed it.
She wanted to go to
Peter's to offer him money
for the pictures,
but when she got there,
he was already dead.
Julie, I know that
Jackie's a friend of yours...
I know, but I believe her.
I've known her for
such a long time,
I would know if she were lying.
And she's telling the truth.
Well, if that's so, then
it must be Gil Altman.
I'm gonna
double-check his alibi.
I would. What I don't get is if
Gil Altman killed Peter Bates,
why'd he steal
Catherine's makeup?
You know a lot of
good-lookin' women.
Ah, yes, I do.
What, did you come here
to talk about celebrities?
No, no, I came to
talk about the, uh,
the night of the murder.
Oh, I-I thought we
already discussed that.
Well, uh, you gave
a barbecue that night.
- Mm-hmm, yeah.
- I talked to
your guests, and they said
they had a wonderful time,
but that you left your
own party for over an hour.
That's what this is all about.
I ran out of propane
gas for the barbecue,
and I had to have
my tank refilled.
Oh... You remember where
you took your tank to be filled?
Sure, I'll... I'll write
it down for you.
Okay.
It should be right here.
Uh, are those the pictures of
Catherine that Peter Bates took?
Uh, yeah. Yeah, they are.
Uh... let me see.
Ah, there it is.
On the night Peter
Bates was killed,
you had some friends
over, uh, for a barbecue.
- That right?
- Yes.
But somewhere around 6:00,
you left your house
for around an hour.
As I told you earlier,
I ran out of propane
gas for my barbecue,
- and I went out to have the tank refilled.
- That's right.
This is the receipt
from Phil's Truck Rental.
Now, you have a standard,
uh, ten-pound tank?
Yes, I do.
Well, look here,
when they filled it,
they could only
get in two pounds.
You had eight pounds
of propane in that tank
when you came in there.
That's enough to cook hamburgers
for this whole
courtroom, maybe more.
Maybe the tank
wasn't hooked up right.
I-I wasn't getting anything.
Oh, it was hooked up right.
You just needed an excuse
to leave your house, go
to Peter Bates's house,
kill him, and come back
without arousing suspicion.
What, are you crazy?!
You know I'm not crazy.
Now, besides that
nearly full propane tank,
this is People's Exhibit 27:
Catherine Welden's makeup kit.
It was found at the
scene of the crime
the night of the murder.
As you can see, it
has six items in it.
Yeah, that's, that's
very interesting.
Catherine tells me the kit that
she left at Peter Bates' house
the night before the
murder had seven items in it.
Catherine should know.
- She created the kit.
- Yeah.
Where's the seventh
item, the concealer?
I don't know.
Your guess is as good as mine.
You know what a concealer is?
Yes, it's used for...
It's used to cover something.
To conceal a blemish,
a mark, a black eye.
I'm sure all killers
hope for a quick kill,
i-immediate death.
But I'm also sure that
sometimes the gun
or the poker or the knife
misses that crucial
spot just an instant,
giving the victim
time to strike out!
Maybe that's what happened
to you when you stabbed
Peter Bates... he lived just
long enough to strike out!
And the result was a black eye.
And you couldn't go home to
your friends with a black eye.
"Where'd you
get it?" they'd say.
And there it was, right in
front of you in the living room...
Her concealer.
With that, you could go
home with no questions asked.
Objection: speculation.
Sustained.
That's what happened, isn't it?
- Mr. Matlock?
- I went
from my house to
Phil's Truck Rentals
and back to my house.
You know, I didn't know
much about makeup
till I got involved
in this case.
Did you know that a
lot of people are allergic
to certain makeups?
No. I...
Uh, would you
tell me, Mr. Altman,
who Dr. Seymour Weinstock is?
He's... he's... he's
my, uh, dermatologist.
When'd you see
him last? Remember?
I... no, I... I don't remember.
You saw him two days
after Peter Bates was killed.
Do you know why you saw him?
Uh, oh, yeah, there...
I do remember why.
I-I had a rash...
A rash or an allergic
reaction to something?
- A rash.
So you put more
makeup on this "rash."
Probably a different kind,
because no one noticed it,
not even your wife.
Objection! Your
Honor, Mr. Matlock
is engaging in
rampant speculation
and then offering up hearsay
to support his
unfounded allegations.
Sustained.
I never went to
Peter Bates's house.
You know Julie March?
Yes, of course I do.
You remember, she
came by your office
a couple days after
Peter Bates was killed?
- Yes, I remember the visit.
- You remember
while you were talking with her,
you tore up those awful
photos of Catherine,
those pictures that Peter was
gonna use to blackmail her with.
Of course I tore them up.
My job is to protect Ms. Welden.
Yeah. You know, the other day...
I found this set of
pictures at your house.
I'll just show them to you.
See?
Where'd you get 'em?
From Peter Bates, I suppose.
But he only made up
four sets of these pictures.
He gave one to Jackie
Flemming, one to Edgar Welden.
He kept one, gave you
one that you tore up.
So I ask you again,
where'd you get these?
Maybe you found 'em
at Peter Bates's house
after you killed him.
But you couldn't
leave 'em there.
What if somebody saw 'em?
Couldn't have that.
Catherine Welden paid you
a lot of money to protect her.
And so that's what
you did, you took them.
- Object!
- For what it's worth,
I don't think you framed
Catherine on purpose.
But when she was arrested,
you didn't come forward!
And money's one thing,
and murder charge is
- something else entirely!
- Object!
Your Honor,
objection! Speculation!
Sustained.
Speculation?
Let me say this...
I'm sure you'll
have to admit, sir...
and you...
that his leaving his house
for an hour, maybe more...
that nearly full
tank of propane...
the missing concealer,
the rash, more makeup,
the set of pictures
that only Peter Bates
should have had...
casts more than a shadow
of doubt that my client
could have in any way
committed this murder.
I wish you all good
caution in your decision.
We find the defendant,
Catherine Welden, not guilty.
Fellas, now come
on. Give us a break.
All the pictures you
want downstairs, all right?
Come on. Knock it off.
Julie, I can't thank you enough.
I decided to tell
Catherine everything.
Good. Make a clean slate of it.
I will.
Ben's offered to take
us all out for dinner.
- Oh, great.
- Great! Where?
Well, it's your
town, you name it.
I must warn you, I have
very expensive taste.
What's money for?
Oh, lucky you!
I'm gonna save this receipt
and write this sucker off.
www.tvsubtitles.net